<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Defs>
	
    <IncidentDef>
		<label>Psionic Brains</label>	
		<description>Generates a tumorous growth within the brain of the colonist granting them a powerful psionic melee attack.</description>
		<defName>SpellPsionicGrowthX</defName>
		<workerClass>CultOfCthulhu.SpellWorker_PsionicGrowth</workerClass>
		<targetType>BaseMap</targetType>
		<letterLabel>to be endowed with psychic power</letterLabel>
		<letterText>felt an intense pressure in their skull and looked on the world with new and strange eyes</letterText>
	</IncidentDef> 

    <IncidentDef>
		<label>Aspect of Xen</label>	
		<description>One of your colonist's limbs spontaneously remanifests as a powerful tentacle.</description>
		<defName>SpellAspectOfXen</defName>
		<workerClass>CultOfCthulhu.SpellWorker_AspectOfCthulhu</workerClass>
		<targetType>BaseMap</targetType>
		<letterLabel>to be endowed with otherworldly parts</letterLabel>
		<letterText>looked around nervously to find who had been endowed with Xen's blessings</letterText>
	</IncidentDef> 
	
    <IncidentDef>
		<label>Orbital Insanity Wave</label>
		<description>Causes a massive wave through the orbital layer of the region. This will cause ships to crash in the vicinity.</description>
		<defName>SpellOrbitalInsanityX</defName>
		<workerClass>CultOfCthulhu.SpellWorker_OrbitalInsanityWave</workerClass>
		<targetType>BaseMap</targetType>
        <letterLabel>to send his dreams into the void as a beacon to those who pass</letterLabel>
		<letterText>felt Xen reach out and draw in vessels for your plunder</letterText>
	</IncidentDef> 
	
	<IncidentDef>
		<label>Terrestrial Insanity Wave</label>
		<description>Causes a massive wave through the terrestrial layer of the region. All enemy humanoid pawns will be riddled with a crippling form of insanity.</description>
		<defName>SpellTerrestrialInsanityX</defName>
		<workerClass>CultOfCthulhu.SpellWorker_TerrestrialInsanityWave</workerClass>
		<targetType>BaseMap</targetType>
        <letterLabel>and ask that he sends your foes into disarray</letterLabel>
        <letterText>cries out with victorious glee as Xen sends their enemies deep into madness</letterText>		
	</IncidentDef> 
	
	
    <IncidentDef>
		<label>Sunken Ship</label>
		<description>Delivers an ancient wreck from a distant seabed to your colony that can provide wood, steel, plasteel, and components when dismantled.</description>
		<defName>SpellSunkenShipX</defName>
		<workerClass>CultOfCthulhu.SpellWorker_SunkenShip</workerClass>
		<targetType>BaseMap</targetType>
        <letterLabel>out of desperation or greed, to deliver wealth from the sea</letterLabel>
        <letterText>is granted a vision of mists unveiling a wreckage from the sea</letterText>		
	</IncidentDef> 
	
    <IncidentDef>
		<label>Treasures of the Deep</label>
		<description>Brings forth lost treasure chests filled with valuable resources such as jade, silver, and gold from ancient ships lost to the abyssal seas.</description>
		<defName>SpellTreasuresOfTheDeepX</defName>
		<workerClass>CultOfCthulhu.SpellWorker_TreasuresOfTheDeep</workerClass>
		<targetType>BaseMap</targetType>
        <letterLabel>out of desperation or greed, to deliver wealth from the sea</letterLabel>
        <letterText>later finds chests of treasure with only damp handprints as evidence of those who left it</letterText>	
	</IncidentDef> 

	  <IncidentDef>
		<label>Defend the Brood</label>
	    <description>Brings a gang of deep ones to stand guard over your colony. Placement of the Sign of Dagon before casting this spell is recommended.</description>
		<defName>SpellDefendTheBroodX</defName>
		<workerClass>CultOfCthulhu.SpellWorker_DefendTheBrood</workerClass>
		<targetType>BaseMap</targetType>
		<category>AllyArrival</category>
		<baseChance>0</baseChance>
		<pointsScaleable>true</pointsScaleable>
        <letterLabel>and ask that he protect his own</letterLabel>
        <letterText>hears a croaking off in the distance. And then another, and then a chorus</letterText>	
	  </IncidentDef>
	
	
	<IncidentDef>
		<label>Bounty of the Sea</label>
		<description>Xen tears a ship from the surface of a distant ocean and delivers its fresh corpse.</description>
		<defName>SpellBountyOfTheSeaX</defName>
		<workerClass>CultOfCthulhu.SpellWorker_BountyOfTheSea</workerClass>
		<targetType>BaseMap</targetType>
        <letterLabel>out of desperation or greed, to deliver wealth from the sea</letterLabel>
        <letterText>hears a crash, then screaming, as the prize is delivered</letterText>		
	</IncidentDef> 
	
	
    <IncidentDef>
		<label>Horny Old Goats</label>
		<description>Summons a herd of black goats to provide your hunters with ample prey to hunt.</description>
		<defName>SpellMotherOfGoatsX</defName>
		<workerClass>CultOfCthulhu.SpellWorker_MotherOfGoats</workerClass>
		<targetType>BaseMap</targetType>
        <letterLabel> to bless them with prey</letterLabel>
        <letterText>can hear the wild screams of goats in the distance</letterText>	
	</IncidentDef> 
	
	<IncidentDef>
		<label>Transmogrify Pets</label>
		<description>Allow Xen to reseed the genetic structure of your beloved pet with extra-dimensional code and tentacles and stuff.</description>
		<defName>SpellTransmogrifyPetsX</defName>
		<workerClass>CultOfCthulhu.SpellWorker_TransmogrifyPets</workerClass>
		<targetType>BaseMap</targetType>
        <letterLabel>to bless their beasts with a touch of its extra-dimensional biology</letterLabel>
        <letterText>looks on as the skin of the chosen creature freaks the hell out.</letterText>		
	</IncidentDef> 
	
	<IncidentDef>
		<label>Extra Dimensional Butthole</label>
		<description>Summons a portal that spews Dark Young monsters to serve you as their loyal master until Xen deems otherwise.</description>
		<defName>SpellWombBetweenWorldsX</defName>
		<workerClass>CultOfCthulhu.SpellWorker_WombBetweenWorlds</workerClass>
		<targetType>BaseMap</targetType>
        <letterLabel>to summon powerful allies</letterLabel>
        <letterText>beholds vine-like tentacles erupt from the ground. The earth heaves and splits open as it craps out a horrendous atrocity.</letterText>
	</IncidentDef>
	
	
    <IncidentDef>
		<label>Starry Wisdom</label>
		<description>Transforms your executioner’s mind into a psychopathic one. Psychopaths will also be turned cannibalistic.</description>
		<defName>SpellStarryWisdomX</defName>
		<workerClass>CultOfCthulhu.SpellWorker_StarryWisdom</workerClass>
		<targetType>BaseMap</targetType>
        <letterLabel>and give the dark one its toll of dreams in exchange for illumination</letterLabel>
        <letterText>has their mind open to the truth</letterText>		
	</IncidentDef> 
	
	<IncidentDef>
		<label>Forbidden Knowledge</label>
		<description>Grants a sizable bonus to your current research project.</description>
		<defName>SpellForbiddenKnowledgeX</defName>
		<workerClass>CultOfCthulhu.SpellWorker_ForbiddenKnowledge</workerClass>
		<targetType>BaseMap</targetType>
        <letterLabel>and ask that he grants forbidden knowledge</letterLabel>
        <letterText>hears dark secrets scratched in the air by a whisper</letterText>		
	</IncidentDef> 
	
	<IncidentDef>
		<label>Chaos Theory</label>
		<description>Accept a deal from Nyarlathotep to live one’s life again. This removes all incapabilities from the executioner and changes their entire backstory.</description>
		<defName>SpellChaosTheoryX</defName>
		<workerClass>CultOfCthulhu.SpellWorker_ChaosTheory</workerClass>
		<targetType>BaseMap</targetType>
        <letterLabel>and petition for another chance to correct mistakes from the past</letterLabel>
        <letterText>is sent back in time to before their birth to relive their life again</letterText>		
	</IncidentDef> 
	
    <IncidentDef>
		<label>Dark Emissary</label>
		<description>A new cult member joins your colony.</description>
		<defName>SpellDarkEmissaryX</defName>
		<workerClass>CultOfCthulhu.SpellWorker_DarkEmissary</workerClass>
		<targetType>BaseMap</targetType>
        <letterLabel>to bolster your ranks with his favoured</letterLabel>
        <letterText>can sense a visitor's arrival</letterText>		
	</IncidentDef> 
	
	    <IncidentDef>
		<label>The King in Yellow, Act I</label>
		<description>Acquire a reproduction of the infamous play, "The King in Yellow." Those exposed to the contents therin are downed and become cult-minded instantly.</description>
		<defName>SpellTheKingInYellowX</defName>
		<workerClass>CultOfCthulhu.SpellWorker_TheKingInYellow</workerClass>
		<targetType>BaseMap</targetType>
        <letterLabel>and petition him to whisper the tale of the the Visitor, who wears no mask, and the doom that followed</letterLabel>
        <letterText>smiles with eagerness. They cannot wait to see how the play ends this time</letterText>	
	</IncidentDef> 
	
	<IncidentDef>
		<label>Summon Byakhee</label>
		<description>Summon a byakhee for defense and transport.</description>
		<defName>SpellSummonByakheeX</defName>
		<workerClass>CultOfCthulhu.SpellWorker_SummonByakhee</workerClass>
		<targetType>BaseMap</targetType>
        <letterLabel>and beseech that he sends one of his hideous star-dwelling steeds</letterLabel>
        <letterText>hears unearthly screams and the beating of leathery wings from above</letterText>		
	</IncidentDef> 
	
	<IncidentDef>
		<label>The King in Yellow, Act II</label>
		<description>A proportion of the inhabitants will fall to dream of the lost city of Carcosa for 5-6 hours and shall awaken deeply calmed for a season.</description>
		<defName>SpellVisionsOfCarcosaX</defName>
		<workerClass>CultOfCthulhu.SpellWorker_VisionsOfCarcosa</workerClass>
		<targetType>BaseMap</targetType>
        <letterLabel>and petition him for visions of the spires and balustrades of the distant and lost city of Carcosa</letterLabel>
        <letterText>feels the tendrils of sleep weave its way into their mind, to pull them away to distant Haydes, where Carcosa sits under black stars</letterText>		
	</IncidentDef> 
	
    <IncidentDef>
		<label>Unspeakable Oath</label>
		<description>The caster is granted a boon by Hastor but upon their death their body becomes his tool and plaything.</description>
		<defName>SpellUnspeakableOathX</defName>
		<workerClass>CultOfCthulhu.SpellWorker_UnspeakableOath</workerClass>
		<targetType>BaseMap</targetType>
        <letterLabel>and swear and an unbreakable oath on his unspoken name</letterLabel>
        <letterText>realises that they are the only one who notices the masked stranger, slender in their yellow robes, and realises that their life is no longer their own</letterText>
	</IncidentDef> 
	
</Defs>